# Wong Yi Zhen Nicholas

+601139391351 / wongviznicholas@gmail.com / https://www.linkedin.com/in/vi-zhen-nicholas-wong-1327b0207

#### **Summary**

2 years of experience in full-stack development that loves challenges and algorithms! Skilled in building responsive UIs with comprehensive unit tests, and specializes in React with TypeScript and does back-end occasionally. Collaborates effectively in team environments and demonstrates strong leadership by taking committee roles in the club and company. Currently on the Get Certified Program for Associate Cloud Engineer by Google Cloud!

#### **Education**

Monash University Malaysia

Feb 2021 – Nov 2023

Bachelor of Computer Science

• GPA: 3.80/4, CGPA: 3.9/4, WAM: 84/100

**Sunway College**Australian Matriculation (AUSMAT)

Jan 2020 – Nov 2020

• ATAR: 97.95

SMK Subang Utama

Jan 2015 - Nov 2019

Secondary School
• SPM: 8A 1B

#### **Experience**

**Dassault Systemes** 

Dec 2023 - Now

## Full Stack Developer

- Act as "Frontend Lead" in a frontend team of 3 for the application after a year, overseeing frontend tasks, peer reviewing FE code, and mitigating risks with the Product Manager
- Developed comprehensive unit tests using React Testing Library and Jasmine to ensure code quality and reliability, achieving a 5% increase in overall test coverage. Created reusable page objects to streamline the end-to-end testing process and improve maintainability.
- Built features in the application using a full stack approach, leveraging React, TypeScript, Java and Spring Boot with REST API
- Served on the committee for the annual team-building event, coordinating with vendors for shirt production and event
  logistics. Successfully sourced a wholesale shirt manufacturer, reducing costs significantly, and ensured clear
  communication between vendors and the committee.

Plentisoft Sdn Bhd Nov 2022 – Feb 2023

## Web Developer

- Developed static web pages using HTML, Tailwind CSS, and JS
- Stored and displayed data collected with graphs and tables using Express, Angular, Angular Material, and Echarts
- Improved the contextual term algorithm by integrating an alternative library to fall back on

#### **Core Skills**

- Technical Skills: Python (Advanced), Java (Advanced), HTML (Intermediate), CSS (Intermediate), TypeScript (Intermediate), SQL (Intermediate), Figma (Intermediate), Docker, GitHub, TensorFlow, Gitlab
- Framework and Libraries: React, Angular, Redux, Chakra UI, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Express, Django, Spring Boot

#### Hackathons

Varsity Hackathon Mar 2023

## Participation Award

- Participated in a 4-day hackathon organized by USM in a team of three, focused on solving various real-world issues such as road accidents, waste management and exposure to career paths
- Designed an innovative waste management platform that employs gamification and a point redemption system, to encourage Malaysians to actively participate in recycling using Figma.
- Figma Prototype Link

KL Mini Hack Feb 2023

## 2<sup>nd</sup> place

• Participated in a 1-week long blockchain hackathon organized by ETHKL in a team of four and created an anonymous and secure voting system using zero-knowledge proof while incentivizing users with a Cabbage Coin!

- Developed the Cabbage coin in a smart contract and displayed the value on the dashboard using React, Express, Solidity and Truffle
- GitHub Repo <u>Link</u>

#### **Projects**

#### **Portfolio**

- Created using NextJS and it took 2 months to design and 1 month of development (excluding working days) to complete it. Inspired from Instagram's User Interface. Comes with Dark Mode and Responsive Design!
- Portfolio Demo Link
- Portfolio Figma Link

## **Hiking Trail Mobile Application**

#### Developer

- Designed a Figma Prototype for a hiking trail mobile application in a team of four, incorporating user preferences and needs by conducting a hiking trail survey with more than 200 respondents
- Created storyboards to visualize the user journey and interactions, leading to the development of a comprehensive hi-fi prototype that enables hikers to find suitable trails based on their preferences.
- Figma Prototype <u>Link</u>

#### Google Search Frontend

#### Developer

- Designed and developed a fully functional frontend for Google Search, Google Image Search and Google Advanced Search using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap
- Demo Link

#### **Extracurricular Activities**

## **Monash Board Gaming Club**

Feb 2022 - Nov 2022

#### President

- Lead a team of 12 committees and mentored them on their responsibilities such as event management and sponsorship negotiation
- Collaborated with 10+ board game cafes to provide special deals to our club members
- Invited Game Masters from SoulMadCafe and Anigames to Monash to introduce different board games to our club members
- Improved Club Instagram insights: +3,900% accounts reached, +264% accounts engaged, +34.4% total followers over 2 months

#### Monash Board Gaming Club

Jul 2021 - Nov 2021

#### Vice President

- Directed the first board game competition and event of the club with a prize pool of RM 100
- Built connections with clubs from Malaysia and Australia

## **Achievements**

## Published Paper: Preprocessing Variations for Classification in Smart Manufacturing Developer/Writer

- Collaborating with my other FYP teammates in university, we managed to publish a paper to the Association for Computing Machinery (ACM). Paper <u>Link</u>.
- Our paper investigates the impact of preprocessing techniques, including brightness and blurriness adjustments, on the performance of deep learning models when dealing with low-quality visual data (edible bird nest) commonly encountered in industrial settings.
- Key Highlights:
  - 1. Successful development of AI prototype for grading Edible Bird's Nest.
  - 2. Potential automation for quality control of Edible Bird's Nest.
  - 3. Utilization of generative AI to create images for training the model.